# Aleksander Fret

tel.: 605 768 401

e-mail: aleksander.fret@op.pl www: aleksander.fret.com.pl

GitHub: www.github.com/aleksanderfret

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/aleksander-fret



## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

JavaScript DeveloperCreating web applications using modern technologies, like JS ES6, TS, React, Redux, Webpack, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB...

some experience with PHP and MySQL,

designing user interfaces (big experience in fhe field of graphics,

interest in UI UX).

Graphic Designer and Cartographer

Extensive editorial practice – designing of publications, DTP,

broad qualifications in the field of graphics software,

Big experience in making various maps.

### EXPERIENCE

Sandstream Development 01/2019–now: position **Software Developer**.

Personal website 09/2018: www.aleksander.fret.com.pl – my online CV. Main

technologies: ES6, React, SASS, PHP.

Udacity 11/2017–08/2018 (student): www.pixel-art-maker.fret.com.pl,

www.memorygame.fret.com.pl, www.arcadegame.fret.com.pl,

www.amusement parks. fret.com.pl.

Eko-Graf 10/2008–01/2019: Cartographer – Map Editor. Duties: designing

of graphic layouts and covers, editorial and cartographic tasks, DTP, creating of advertising materials, preparing for printing.

WilMat 10/2016: www.wilmat.com.pl.

Personal websites 01/2015: www.ewa.fret.com.pl.

Others 11/2012: Via Mercatorum, website, logo, advertising leaflet...

04/2007-07/2008: SeaStar, Cartographer,

11/2005–12/2006: Nowa Era, Author: *Statistical tables*, 09/2004–03/2005: Wydawnictwo Marek Rożak, Cartographer.

#### EDUCATION

Udacity 11.2017–08.2018: Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

**Program** (scholarship from Google).

Certain courses and trainings

React 16 – the complete guide; The Complete Sass & SCSS Course; PHP – developing CMS; PHP, MySQL, JS.

University of Wroclaw

10.1999–07.2005: bachelor's degree in *Geography*, master's degree in *Geography*, specialization in *Cartography*.

# QUALIFICATIONS

## Programming

JS ES6, TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js, Express.js. MongoDB, Mongoose, JQuery, SASS, CSS, HTML, RWD, accessibility, Webpack, Gulp, Git, SEO, PHP, MySOL, Twig.

#### Graphics software

CorelDRAW, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Photo-Paint, Figma.

#### Others

English language (b1), Global Mapper.

## ACHIEVEMENTS

Award in the competition organized by Ministry of Transport and Construction for master thesis *Atlas regionalny woje-wództwa łódzkiego*.

III prize for "[...] modern editorial style, usability [...]", *Wrocław – przewodnik* (J. Czerwiński, Eko-Graf), XX Ogólnopolski Przegląd Książki Krajoznawczo-Turystycznej. Scope of work: graphic design and creation, DTP.

# PERSONAL TRAITS

Creative, with attention to detail, reliable, responsible, strongly involved.

#### INTERESTS

Playing the guitar, listening to the music, board games, fantasy literature, games and films, football, mountain hiking.